Finding Aid for the A&M Records Records PASC-M.0269
UCLA Library Special Collections
- Sound recordings, 1910-1999; Series 12.
  - Commercial popular music: 33 1/3 rpm LP sound recordings, Subseries 6.
    - Stop Making Sense, 1984 (Box 47, Folder 6)
      Publisher no.: 25186-1
    - Talkshow, 1984; 1 12" sound disc (Box 43, Folder 18)
      Publisher no.: SP 070041
      Head Over Heels -- Turn To You -- You Thought -- Beneath The Blue Sky -- Forget That Day -- I'm The Only One -- Yes Or No -- Capture The Light -- I'm With You -- Mercenary.
      Disc only.
    - Ta Mara & The Seen, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 18)
      Publisher no.: SP 6-5078
    - Atto III, "Drumtheatre" (Box 44, Folder 21)
      Publisher no.: C60 28299 009
    - JT (Box 170, Folder 15)
      Publisher no.: 34811
      Your Smiling Face -- There We Are -- Honey Don't Leave L.A. -- Another Grey Morning -- Bartender's Blues -- Secret O' Life -- Handy Man -- I Was Only Telling A Lie -- Looking For Love On Broadway -- Terra Nova -- Traffic Jam -- If I Keep My Heart Out Of Sight.
    - Symphony #2 ("Little Russian"), 1980 (Box 46, Folder 11)
      Publisher no.: ARL1-3352
    - Flashback, 1987 (Box 36, Folder 4)
      Publisher no.: SP 3910
    - Gotta Give A Little Love, 1984 (Box 43, Folder 26)
      Publisher no.: GG-81203
    - Swamp (Box 44, Folder 6)
      Publisher no.: MCA 42226
    - Toto (Box 170, Folder 19)
      Publisher no.: JC 35317
      Child's Anthem -- I'll Supply the Love -- Georgy Porgy -- Manuela Run -- You Are the Flower -- Girl Goodbye -- Takin' It Back -- Rockmaker -- Hold the Line -- Angela.
    - Can't Give It Up, 1975 (Box 45, Folder 14)
      Publisher no.: NSPL 18467
    - Bachelorette, 1991 (Box 32, Folder 18)
      Publisher no.: 75021 7285 1
    - Ideola, 1987 (Box 34, Folder 15)
      Publisher no.: SP 755
    - Wonderland, 1987 (Box 41, Folder 22)
      Publisher no.: BT 85140
    - Riverdeep - Mountain High, 1 12" sound disc (Box 183)
      Publisher no.: SP 3170
      River Deep-Mountain High -- I Idolize You -- A Love Like Yours -- A Fool in Love -- Make 'em Wait -- Hold on Baby -- I'll Never Need More Than This -- Save the Last Dance for Me -- Oh Baby -- Every Day I Have to Cry -- Such a Fool for You -- It's Gonna Work Out Fine.
    - Labour of Love, 1983 (Box 33, Folder 16)
      Publisher no.: SP-6-4980
    - Little Baggariddim (Box 33, Folder 20)
      Publisher no.: SP 6-5090
    - CCCP - Live in Moscow, 1986 (Box 38, Folder 16)
      Publisher no.: SP 5168
    - The Lucy Show, 1985 (Box 33, Folder 19)
      Publisher no.: SP 6-5088
    - Now, 1975 (Box 45, Folder 13)
      Publisher no.: NSPL 18470
    - The Best Things in Life Are Free (Box 32, Folder 4)
      Publisher no.: 31458 8003 1
      Also performed by Janet Jackson.
    - The Best Of Gino Vannelli (Box 35, Folder 13)
      Publisher no.: SP 3729
    - The Best Things In Life Are Free, 1992 (Box 45, Folder 43)
      Also performed by: Janet Jackson.
    - Chariots of Fire, music from the original motion picture soundtrack, 1981 (Box 169, Folder 6)
      Publisher no.: PD-1-6335
      Titles -- Five Circles -- Abraham's Theme -- Eric's Theme -- 100 Metres -- Jerusalem -- Chariots of Fire.
    - Soil Festivities, 1984 (Box 169, Folder 7)
      Publisher no.: 823 396-1 Y-1
      Movement 1 -- Movement 2 -- Movement 3 -- Movement 4 -- Movement 5 -- Movement 6.
    - Pedro Vargas Canta a Miguel Matamoros, 1969; 1 12" sound disc (Box 46, Folder 34)
      Publisher no.: CAM-402
      2 copies, both autographed
    - Viva Vargas!, 1969; 1 12" sound disc (Box 46, Folder 35)
      Also performed by: Adolfo Guzman and his orchestra.
    - Fame, the original motion picture soundtrack, 1980 (Box 169, Folder 14)
      Publisher no.: RX-1-3080
      Fame -- Out Here On My Own -- Hot Lunch Jam -- Dogs In the Yard -- Red Light Is It Okay If I Call You Mine? -- Never Alone -- Ralph and Monty (Dressing Room Piano) -- I Sing the Body Electric.
    - Saturday Night Fever, the original motion picture soundtrack, 1977 (Box 169, Folder 15)
      Publisher no.: RS-2-4001
      Stayin' Alive -- How Deep Is Your Love -- If I Can't Have You -- A Fifth of Beethoven -- Jive Tallkin' -- K-Jee -- Calypso Breakdown -- More Than A Woman -- Night Fever -- Boogie Shoes -- Disco Inferno -- You Should Be Dancing -- Open Sesame -- More Than A Woman -- Manhattan Skyline -- Night On Disco Mountain -- Salsation.
    - Grease, the original motion picture soundtrack, 1978 (Box 169, Folder 16)
      Publisher no.: RS-2-4002
      Grease -- Summer Nights -- Hopelessly Devoted To You -- You're the One That I Want -- Sandy -- Beauty School Drop-Out -- Look At Me, I'm Sandra Dee -- Greased Lightnin' -- It's Raining On Prom Night -- Alone At the Drive-In Movie -- Blue Moon -- Rock n' Roll Is Here TO Stay -- Those Magic Changes -- Hound Dog -- Born To Hand Jive -- Tears On My Pillow -- Mooning -- Freddy My Love -- Rock n' Roll Party Queen -- There Are Worse Things I Could Do -- Look At Me, I'm Sandra Dee -- We Go Together -- Love Is A Many Splendored Thing -- Grease.
    - The Smithsonian Collection of Classic Jazz (Box 169, Folder 20)
      Publisher no.: P6 11891
      Maple Leaf Rag / Scott Joplin -- Maple Leaf Rag / Jelly Roll Morton -- Hellhound On My Trail / Robert Johnson -- St. Louis Blues -- Lost Your Head Blues / Bessie Smith -- Dippermouth Blues / King Oliver's Creole Jazz Band -- Grandpa's Spells -- Dead Man Blues -- Black Bottom Stomp / Jelly Roll Morton -- Cake Walking Babies / Red Onion Jazz Babies -- Blue Horizon / Sidney Bechet -- Carolina Shout / James P. Johnson -- Struttin' with Some Barbeque -- S.O.L. Blues (excerpt) -- Potato Head Blues (excerpt) / Louis Armstrong -- Hotter Than That -- West End Blues / Louis Armstrong -- Weather Bird / Louis Armstrong and Earl Hines -- Sweethearts On Parade -- I Gotta Right To Sing the Blues / Louis Armstrong -- Riverboat Shuffle -- Singin' the Blues / Frankie Trumbauer -- The Stampede -- Wrappin' It Up / Fletcher Henderson -- Moten Swing / Benny Moten's Kansas City Orchestra -- I Ain't Got Nobody / Fats Waller -- Honky Tonk Train / Meade Lux Lewis -- Body and Soul / Benny Goodman Trio -- Body and Soul -- The Man I Love / Coleman Hawkins -- He's Funny That Way -- All Of Me / Billie Holiday -- You'd Be So Nice To Come Home to / Ella Fitzgerald -- Willow Weep For Me -- Too Marvelous For Words / Art Tatum -- Lunceford Special / Jimmy Lunceford -- Rockin' Chair / Gene Krupa -- I Can't Believe that You're in Love with Me (excerpt) / Roy Eldridge and Benny Carter -- When Lights Are Low / Lionel Hampton -- Doggin' Around -- Taxi War Dance / Count Basie -- Lester Leaps In / Count Basie's Kansas City Seven -- I Found A New Baby / Benny Goodman Sextet -- blues sequence (from Breakfast Feud) / Charlie Christian with the Benny Goodman Sextet -- East St. Louis Toodle-Oo / Duke Ellington and his Orchestra -- New East St. Louis Toodle-Oo -- Creole Rhapsody -- Harlem Air Shaft -- Concerto for Cootie -- In a Mellotone -- Ko-ko -- Blue Serge / Duke Ellington -- I Got Rhythm / Don Byas -- I Can't Get Started -- Shaw 'Nuff / Dizzy Gillespie -- KoKo -- Embraceable You -- Embraceable You (alternate version) -- Klacktoveedsedsteen -- Little Benny -- Parker's Mood / Charlie Parker -- Fantasy on "Frankie and Johnny" / Errol Garner -- Somebody Loves Me / Bud Powell -- Dancing in the Dark -- Ain't No Use / Sarah Vaughan -- Crosscurrent / Lennie Tristano -- Boplicity / Miles Davis -- Lady Bird / Tadd Dameron's Sextet -- Bikini / Dexter Gordon -- Misterioso -- Criis Cross -- Evidence -- Smoke Gets In Your Eyes -- I Should Care -- blues improvisation (excerpt from Bag's Groove by Miles Davis All Stars) / Thelonious Monk -- Summertime / Miles Davis with Gil Evans Orchestra -- Blue 7 / Sonny Rollins -- Django / Modern Jazz Quartet -- Hora Decubitus / Charlie Mingus -- Pent-Up House / Sonny Rollins Plus Four -- Enter Evening / Cecil Taylor -- So What / Miles Davis -- Lonely Woman -- Congeniality -- Free Jazz (excerpt) / Ornette Coleman -- Alabama / John Coltrane.
    - Music from the Woody Allen Film, Manhattan, Including Selections from the Original Soundtrack, 1979 (Box 170, Folder 23)
      Publisher no.: JS 36020
      Rhapsody In Blue -- Land Of the Gay Caballero, Someone To Watch Over Me -- I've Got A Crush On You; Do, Do, Do -- Mine -- He Loves and She Loves; Bronco Busters -- Oh, Lady Be Good; S'Wonderful -- Love Is Here To Stay -- Sweet and Low-Down; Blue, Blue, Blue; Embraceable You -- He Loves and She Loves; Love Is Sweeping the Country; Land of the Gay Caballero; Strike Up the Band; But Not For Me.
    - The Breakfast Club, Original Motion Picture Soundtrack, 1985 (Box 171, Folder 3)
      Publisher no.: SP 5045
      Don't You (Forget About Me) / Simple Minds -- Waiting / Elizabeth Daily -- Fire In the Twilight / Wang Chung -- I'm the Dude (instrumental) -- Heart Too Hot To Hold / Jesse Johnson & Stephanie Spruill -- Dream Montage (instrumental) -- We Are Not Alone / Karla DeVito -- The Reggae (instrumental) -- Didn't I Tell You / Joyce Kennedy -- Love Theme (instrumental).
    - Lost In the Starts, the music of Kurt Weill, 1985 (Box 171, Folder 35)
      Publisher no.: SP 9-5104
      Mahagonny Songspiel / Steve Weisberg -- The Ballad of Mac the Knife / Sting and Dominic Muldowney -- The Cannon Song / The Fowler Brothers with Stanard Ridgway -- Ballad of the Soldier's Wife / Marianne Faithfull and Chris Spedding -- Johnny Johnson Medley / Van Dyke Parks -- Alabama Song / Ralph Schuckett with Richard Butler, Bob Dorough, Ellen Shipley, and John Petersen -- Youkali Tango / Armadillo String Quartet -- Der Kleine Lieutenant des Lieben Gottes (The Little Lieutenant of the Living God) / John Zorn -- September Song / Lou Reed -- Lost In the Stars / Carla Bley with Phil Woods -- What Keeps Mankind Alive? / Tom Waits -- Surabaya Johnny / Dagmar Krause -- Oh Heavenly Salvation / Mark Bingham with Johnny Adams and Aaron Neville -- Call From the Grave; Ballad In Which Macheath Begs All Men For Forgiveness / Todd Rundgren with Gary Windo -- Speak Low / Charlie Haden with Sharon Freeman -- In No Man's Land / Van Dyke Parks.
    - Blood Makes Noise (Box 32, Folder 8)
      Publisher no.: 31458 8046 1
    - Solitude Standing, 1987 (Box 37, Folder 20)
      Publisher no.: SP-5136
    - [Selections], 1986 April 14 (Box 62, Folder 6)
      Fools Paradise -- Magic Smile -- Interlude -- Tonto.
      Side A. Mastercut.
    - Zazu, 1986 (Box 171, Folder 27)
      Publisher no.: sp 6-5016
      Fool's Paradise -- Magic Smile -- Interlude -- Tonto -- Sunday -- Taxi -- 2nd Emotion -- Boxs.
    - Seems You're Much Too Busy (Box 32, Folder 7)
      Publisher no.: 31458 8083 1
    - Maria Vidal, 1987 (Box 33, Folder 21)
      Publisher no.: SP 6-5160
    - Strange Situation (Box 41, Folder 13)
      Publisher no.: 812-339
    - Reggae Soul & Rock 'n' Roll, 1976 (Box 45, Folder 8)
      Publisher no.: NSPL 18487
    - Dancing On The Edge Of The World (Box 48, Folder 10)
      Publisher no.: WH 0109
    - Madness Of It All, 1986 (Box 38, Folder 8)
      Publisher no.: SP-5132
    - That's What Time It Is, 1981 (Box 37, Folder 7)
      Publisher no.: SP-4880
    - Black On Blue, 1982 (Box 46, Folder 5)
      Publisher no.: AHL1-4247
    - Lost In The Stars, 1985; 1 12" sound disc (Box 34, Folder 16)
      The music of Kurt Weill.
    - The Tip of the Weisberg, 1 12" sound disc (Box 44, Folder 33)
      Publisher no.: NR7
    - The Right Night and Barry White, 1987 (Box 38, Folder 13)
      Publisher no.: SP 5154
    - The Righ Night and Barry White, 1987; 1 12" sound disc (Box 183)
      Sho' You Right -- For Your Love (I'll Do Most Anything) -- There's a Place (Where Love Never Ends) -- Love is in Your Eyes -- Theme -- The Right Night -- I'm Ready for Love -- Theme -- Share -- Who's the Fool.
    - Classics (Box 36, Folder 23)
      Publisher no.: SP 4701
    - Einstein On The Beach, 1979 (Box 47, Folder 16)
      Publisher no.: Tom-4-2901
    - Chronicles, 1987 (Box 43, Folder 12)
      Publisher no.: 25660-1
    - Wintersong; tomorrow is my dancing day (Box 44, Folder 1)
      Publisher no.: LM0012
    - Conscience, 1988 (Box 43, Folder 13)
      Publisher no.: 7 90915-1
    - The Wonder Of Stevie (Box 43, Folder 4)
      Publisher no.: JSA 6253
    - Down For The Count, 1985 (Box 38, Folder 5)
      Publisher no.: SP 5101
    - Upstairs At Eric's (Box 44, Folder 31)
      Publisher no.: 540037
    - 90125, 1983; 1 12" sound disc (Box 41, Folder 5)
      Publisher no.: 90125
      Owner of a Lonely Heart -- Hold On -- It Can Happen -- Changes -- Cinema -- Leave It -- Our Song -- City of Love -- Hearts.
    - The Yoav Chamber Ensemble, 1980 (Box 45, Folder 37)
      Publisher no.: ORS 80388
    - Rosie Vela, 1986 (Box 33, Folder 17)
      Publisher no.: SP 6-5016
  - Jazz instruction: 33 1/3 rpm LP sound recordings, Subseries 7.
    - A New Approach To Jazz Improvisation (Box 43, Folder 6)
      Publisher no.: JA 2025
    - Learn To Improvise Jazz, 1981 (Box 43, Folder 8)
      Publisher no.: JA 1237-1237
    - Movin' On, 1974 (Box 43, Folder 9)
      Publisher no.: JA 1213
      Volume 4 of A New Approach To Jazz Improvisation.
    - The II-V7-I progression: a new approach to jazz improvisation for all instruments, 1974 (Box 43, Folder 10)
      Publisher no.: JA 1212
    - Nothin' but blues: volume 2 of a new approach to jazz improvisation for all instruments, 1981 (Box 43, Folder 11)
      Publisher no.: JA 1211
    - Wayne Shorter Jazz Classics For You To Play, 1985; 2 12" sound discs (Box 43, Folder 7)
      Publisher no.: JA 1250
      Jazz Classics, vol. 33. Also performed by: Ron Carter and Adam Nussbaum. Play a long book and two record set.
  - Motion picture soundtracks: 33 1/3 rpm LP sound recordings, Subseries 8.
    - A Night In Heaven, 1983; 1 12" sound disc (Box 37, Folder 12)
      Publisher no.: SP-4966
      Original motion picture soundtrack.
    - Running Scared (Box 44, Folder 8)
      Publisher no.: MCA-6169
      Music from the motion picture.
    - Star Struck (Box 44, Folder 26)
      Publisher no.: L37783
      Soundtrack.
    - Young Einstein (Box 44, Folder 28)
      Publisher no.: TVL 93282 (RML 53282)
  - Windham Hill: 33 1/3 rpm LP sound recordings, Subseries 9.
    - From the Album, "Vapor Drawings" wh-1027 (Box 48, Folder 9)
      Publisher no.: WS-17258
    - Piano Sampler (Box 48, Folder 13)
      Publisher no.: WH-1040
    - Gyuto monks (Box 48, Folder 16)
      Publisher no.: WH-2001
    - High Plains (Box 48, Folder 12)
      Publisher no.: WH-1037
    - The Story of Naomi Uemura (Box 48, Folder 17)
      Publisher no.: WHP-28041
  - CDs, 1987-1998; Subseries 10.
    Items are arranged alphabetically by performer, and then alphabetically by album title.
    - Iodine, 1998 (Box 66, Folder 11)
      Publisher no.: 9144-2
    - 11 Transistor, 1997 (Box 66, Folder 8)
    - Barefoot Servants, 1994 (Box 66, Folder 7)
      Publisher no.: 57503
    - Subcircus, 1997 (Box 66, Folder 6)
      Publisher no.: 50026
    - From the top, 1991 (Box 67, Folder 1)
      Publisher no.: 7 31454 0000 2
      4 compact disc box set
    - From the top, 1991 (Box 67, Folder 2)
      Publisher no.: 75021 6875 2
      4 CD box set
    - The compact disc collection: limited edition, 1989 (Box 67, Folder 3)
      12 CD box set serial number 0004
    - The compact disc collection: limited edition, 1989 (Box 67, Folder 4)
      serial no 0005 12 CD box set
    - Vegas, 1997 (Box 66, Folder 1)
      Publisher no.: OPRD-30003
    - Hits and More, The, 1996 (Box 66, Folder 2)
    - Beyond category.., 1990 (Box 67, Folder 5)
      2 CD box set
    - U. S. Songs, 1998 (Box 66, Folder 3)
      Publisher no.: 68
      Contents: Dionysus Burning -- Miracle -- The Watermark High.
    - Transition, 1987 (Box 66, Folder 4)
      Publisher no.: 33CY-1484
      Cover only
    - One Hand Washes the Other (Box 66, Folder 12)
    - Songwriter, 1989 (Box 66, Folder 10)
      Publisher no.: PJ1
    - Blue skies forever: limited edition, 1998 (Box 67, Folder 6)
      Publisher no.: WJPJ 079
      4 cd box set
    - Mood Swings, 1999 (Box 66, Folder 9)
    - Stepchild, 1995 (Box 66, Folder 5)
  - Miscellaneous: 33 1/3 rpm LP sound recordings, Subseries 11.
    - [Unidentified], 1 12" sound disc (Box 44, Folder 17)
      Publisher no.: C60 27171 008
    - Do-It-Yourself, The Music of Cole Porter, 1 12" sound disc (Box 44, Folder 29)
      Publisher no.: J55
    - A Colorful Collection of Radio Commericals, 1965; 1 7" sound disc (Box 57, Folder 19)
      Meet the Paint -- Stan Freberg Redecorates lake Michigan -- Painting on Radio? -- Pittsburgh Paints Theatre of the Air (Moby Dick, Painton Place, The Fall of the House of Usher, Love Song to a Drab Room.
    - The Funniest Hours in the History of Radio, 1 12" sound disc (Box 61, Folder 2)
      Publisher no.: 5NLR150
- Video recordings, 1983-1991; Series 13.
  THIS SERIES CONTAINS UNPROCESSED AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS: Audiovisual materials are not currently available for access and will require further processing and assessment. If you have questions about this material please email spec-coll@library.ucla.edu.
  - Best of Ed Sullivan Show, 1991 February 17 (Box 70, Folder 2)
    Part 1.
  - Black or White (Box 70, Folder 7)
    MTV production.
  - The Carpenters, VHS tape (Box 70, Folder 3)
    This tape is digitaly matered stereo hi-fi and cannot be played in mono without sound quality loss
  - Hero, 1989 June 8; VHS tape (Box 70, Folder 4)
    On label, "Viewing Copy."
  - Herb & Jerry's announcement, VHS Tape (Box 70, Folder 5)
    Title from label. Duration: ca. 5:00.
  - Home Safety, 1989 January 13; VHS Tape (Box 71, Folder 3)
  - Jerry Moss Interview (Box 70, Folder 6)
    London, NTSC copy
  - Motown 25, 1983 May 16; VHS tape (Box 70, Folder 1)
    Duration: 2 hours.
  - Nat & Theresa (Chronology), VHS Tape (Box 71, Folder 1)
  - Nostradamus, 1991 February 18; VHS Tape (Box 71, Folder 2)
  - Racetrack, VHS Tape (Box 71, Folder 4)
    PBS 90 min
  - Solo rock performers (Box 71, Folder 6)
  - Thanks. Brooklyn College, VHS Tape (Box 71, Folder 7)
  - Thomas Hearings, VHS Tape (Box 71, Folder 5)
    On label, "Saturday Night Live."
  - Yo! Its May '89 Compilation Reel, 1989; VHS Tape (Box 71, Folder 8)
    Nineteen Forever (Joe Jackson) -- Wonderful Life (Black) -- I Don't Even Mind (Scott Grimes) -- Reprobate's Hymn (Thrashing Doves) -- This Is Your Land (Simple Minds).
    Performed by: Joe Jackson, Black, Scott Grimes, Thrashing Doves and Simple Minds.